<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>A collection of writings that strive, often unsucessfully, to capture the beautiful complexity of the human experience.</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Segway</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this from a local coffee shop in Frederick, MD, all the way back in the United States of America. After more than 5 months of travel and study, the long trip has come to an end. With my outbound flight bearing down on me, I spent the last weeks of my time in Australia squeezing out every last drop of value I could. Many tasks got unceremoniously labeled as an “America Problem” and ignored. Blogging was most certainly one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this post, I hope to catch up to the present and give myself one last shot at reflection. Maybe give a few shout-outs along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished up my final exams. I took a leap of courage and went on my first ever truly solo trip.  Four days to explore one of the largest cities in Australia, Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/brighton.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Brighton Beach Boxes&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/brighton.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/lane.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Melbourne&apos;s Laneways&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/lane.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/kilda_selfie.jpg&quot; title=&quot;St. Kilda with Melbourne in the background&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/kilda_selfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Melbourne Selfies
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring a city on my own was an amazing growing experience. I will be the first to say it wasn’t the most enjoyable trip I’ve taken, but it definitely was one of the most rewarding. I took the trip with the intention of forcing myself out of my comfort zone. One of my long time personal projects has been to get over my anxiety of talking to strangers. Before the trip, I was definitely capable of it, but by no means comfortable. Another benefit of the trip is that when you are alone, you get to do exactly what you want to do. There is no worrying if one activity will upset the group, etc.. It teaches you what kind of traveler you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving back at Newcastle from Melbourne, the goodbyes began. Many of the friends I had made over the course of the semester were either preparing to go off on month long trips, or head back home. These few days were a flurry of packing, farewells, and last minute excursions to cafes and beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo7_19/newy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;newy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo7_19/wes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next thing I knew, it was time to meet up with Dani at the Sydney Airport! After one day rest in Sydney, we were moving up the coast to Brisbane and the Gold Coast, then finally up to Cairns, the Daintree Rainforest, and the Great Barrier Reef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo7_19/map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trip served as the final hurrah for my time in Australia. It was neat to share just a little bit of my study abroad experience with my sister, and to explore such amazing locations together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/cape_trib.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Cape Tribulation&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/cape_trib.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/milla_milla.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Milla Milla Falls, infamous for the hair flipping shampoo commercial&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/milla_milla.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/mossman.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mossman Gorge&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/mossman.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/oasis.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Traveller&apos;s Oasis Hostel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/oasis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/opera.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Obligatory Sydney Opera House Pic&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/opera.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/surfers.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Surfer&apos;s Paradise&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/surfers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/sus_bridge.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mossman Gorge Bridge&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/sus_bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/yogi.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Yoga at Surfer&apos;s Paradise&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo7_19/yogi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Traversing the East Coast of Australia
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this trip finished, a few days of packing and final goodbyes led to the 36 hour travel day that has brought me here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to sit next to a very good friend for the 14 hour leg from SYD to LAX, helping pass the time and fend off sleep. For my next two flights home, I managed to stay awake until I finally fell asleep at a normal time. So far, it seems like my strategy effectively removed any jetlag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming back home was very weird. With 6 months of new experiences behind me, I came back to a house, room and city that are almost exactly the same as I left them. I changed, my American life didn’t. One word, eerie. So, in order to adjust back, I quickly made changes to reflect my new experiences. It’s still an ongoing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just looking back at any of the pictures on my phone, I am struck by hundreds of memories and small moments all associated with a single picture. To tell the truth, the moments that give me the most joy are all hidden in the details. Its the memories evoked by the picture, the punchline of a joke, or the beginning of a friendship, that hit me the hardest. The common thread with all these moments? It’s the people. The amazing landscapes and views found by traveling are just the backdrop for the real show. Its through the people that you learn about the country’s culture, yourself, and create new memories. The prize of travel is not a destination or a photo opportunity, its human connection.  I am immensely thankful for all of the wonderful people I have had the privilege of meeting, and can only begin to speak about the impact they have had on my life. My world has been redefined, and I couldn’t be happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo7_19/fam.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;fam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 09:34:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Segway</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Segway</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Beginning of the End</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;1:40 AM, June 3rd - Last week of class&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could be asleep tonight, I definitely would be. Unfortunately, the Australian chill also extends to lab partners, and specifically to deadlines. The good comes with the bad. I figured that I could at least do something productive while I waited for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:15 PM, June 13th - 2 Exams down, 2 to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler, I didn’t stay up long enough to contribute anything more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how many people would believe me if I said that such a late night is pretty uncommon for me now. Hey, four months is a pretty long time, things can change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I’m really enjoying the Australian education system. To put it simply, there is less pressure to get the grade, both on the professor and students parts. Take a look around the library late at night, or on the weekend and it is 95% international students. The campus is a ghost town after the sun falls. I hardly ever see any of my local friends studying for longer than two hours at a time. The culture has a good idea of work life balance, an idea that sometimes results in submitting lab reports just a few days late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course curriculums incorporated one or two weeks of review in addition to a one to two week reading day period. The lowest grade, High Distinction (HD) starts at an 85. Grades are not displayed with projected results (e.g. using all assignments graded, your mark in the class is an 85), but more concretely as points you have already earned. So its not unusual to hear someone say they have a 40% in a class. In fact, with a finals system worth 50% of your grade, a 40% is pretty good. The decrease in pressure lets you focus on learning the content of the course, rather than learning to pass the exam. A subtle but distinct difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My courses are pass/fail when they are taken back to the US, so all I need is about a 10% on most of my exams. That doesn’t stop me from trying to get a 100. Either way, that kernel of knowledge helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four months out of a total of five. Classes are over, and just earlier I finished my second exam. With more studying to come and some final trips in the works, there aren’t very many days left. One month used to sound a lot longer. Some international students without final exams have already returned home, or are on their final voyages as we speak. The social life has changed from “we should hang out” to “I want to make sure I see you again before I leave!”. Grocery trips need to be a little more thoughtful, supplies are being rationed, and people are realizing just how many things you can accumulate in four months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first big thing that I did since the last post was to take a trip to the center of the continent, affectionately known as the “Red Centre”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo6_14/map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to give you a sense of scale, Alice Springs, the closest civilization to Uluru-Kata Tjuta National Park is 1,500 kilometers (940 miles) from anything resembling a small town. We were smack dab in the middle of the outback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this trip I was traveling with a slightly different group of friends, both coincidentally from the North East of the US. As remote as it is, when we were planning the trip we did   of a lot of research into the benefits of renting a car vs booking a tour (also into cheap flights). Eventually we settled on a 3 day rock tour. Thanks to our obsession with cheap flights, it only took a few all nighters to make it there! Thousands of driven kilometers after we landed, we returned to the airport. The tour guide was amazing, and as a group of traveling youth, it was a great experience. Nights sleeping under the stars, with no light pollution, will spoil almost any stargazing I will ever do again. Sunrise and sunset at Uluru, the local culture and history, and stunning landscape made it an unforgettable trip. Imagine ranch country, maybe somewhere in Texas or similar states. Give it an Australian twist and boom, you’ve got it pictured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/camp.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sleeping under the stars&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/camp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/king.jpg&quot; title=&quot;King&apos;s Canyon, Watarrka National Park, NT&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/king.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/red.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Red Centre&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/red.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/vow.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Valley of the Winds, Kata Tjuta&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/vow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/sunset.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Uluru Sunset&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/alice.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Alice Springs, NT&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/alice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Red Centre Trip
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve kept at my many hobbies, and seen significant progress in each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the university’s volleyball team prepares for their national competition, Unigames, practices have been carrying on. By far the least experienced and skilled player on the court, I have been fortunate to learn and play alongside some amazing people. I never realized how complicated synchronized movements and positioning can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the regular top rope climbing I’ve been doing, I also have had the fortune of going bouldering at a gym off campus a few times. While climbing on a rope can be fun, its completely different from bouldering. A top rope climb is a marathon, where you can ascend four to five stories in a single climb, with a few particularly challenging sections here and there. Bouldering is more of a sprint with nothing but challenging sections. The climbs are shorter, about one story at its max. For my own record, and in the Australian grading system, my top rope climbs are hovering at about 16, while my bouldering is roughly at V4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/fcbb.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Belaying!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/fcbb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/bcfb.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Top Rope Climbing&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/bcfb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/fhbb.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Stumped&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/fhbb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/bb.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Bouldering&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/bb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/bhb.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Partners Bouldering, must stay in contact at all times!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/bhb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Climbing
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ve been surfing a bit too. I had the privilege of joining a 6 week surf program centered about wellness, social activities, and morning routines. To get to the beach in time, I have been waking up at 5am for a few days each week. Watching the sunrise, catching a coffee, and going for a surf before 9 is a magical feeling.  Slowly but surely, I’m turning into a morning person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/casual_surf.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Cold sand is not fun&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/casual_surf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/surff.jpg&quot; title=&quot;My standup is still a work in progress&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/surff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/surf.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Not particularly steady&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/surf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/wow.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Waves of Wellness&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo6_14/wow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Surfing
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, there were a few adventures on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo6_14/cooler.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cool&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo6_14/blu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blue&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 09:34:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Beginning-of-the-End</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Beginning-of-the-End</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Identity</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it seems I have fallen a bit behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something proud in that. I am busy enough living that I have trouble sitting down to talk. Or, perhaps more accurately, it isn’t a priority. In a world tied to the cultivation of an &lt;em&gt;image&lt;/em&gt;, so many people are forgetting that an experience can be so much more powerful than a post. I think that slowly, I am finding the balance between sharing my experiences and actually experiencing them. For all the negatives of social media, there is nothing wrong with its core idea. Human connection and storytelling have power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets rewind a bit, to early April. A time that feels a little bit to recent to be almost a month in the past. Funny thing, time. I was emerging from a harrowing work week, me and my friends set off on a 5 hour journey for a club sponsored trip to the Blue Mountains, a national park outside of Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\images\wo5_05\bluemap.png&quot; alt=&quot;blue&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to simply say I was excited would be an injustice. For more than 10 years, I have spent at least a little bit of my summer on trails. From Alaska to New York, our family has covered a lot of ground.  To my sister’s chagrin, little to none of it could be described with the word “sand”.  I have to say, I have learned to enjoy the beach. Although Bondi and Manly might be famous, the beaches at Newcastle are locally known for their world class surf and sand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 3 month hobby, however, still can’t compare to one a decade in the making. So the prospect of hiking and anything labeled as a “mountain” was exhilarating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all my anticipation, this trip was not anything like what I had experienced with my family. Staying in a hostel with over a hundred fellow students, hiking for 8+ hours, two days straight, and doing it all with people your age. Now, to some of you, I’m sure this isn’t appealing at all. One thing I’ve learned is that sometimes knowing what you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; like is just as useful as learning what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I liked this trip. Walking at the front of the group, with rainforest at my front and friends at my back, I knew. I knew that &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; was something I wanted to do for the rest of my life. Something I wanted to be a part of my life. A piece of the puzzle filled in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/explorers.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Explorers&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/explorers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/feet.jpg&quot; title=&quot;I was there!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/feet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo Credit to Lauren!&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/hostel.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Our accomodation&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/hostel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the botanical garden&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/lensflare.jpg&quot; title=&quot;PC to Steven&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/lensflare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Probably the sketchiest hostel in Sydney...&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/riverstop.jpg&quot; title=&quot;One of my favorite pictures!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/riverstop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ANZAC Memorial Reflecting Pool&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/sisters.jpg&quot; title=&quot;3 Sisters at sunset!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/blue/sisters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sydney Harbor Bridge with Lauren&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Blue Mountains
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I hadn’t been cooking meat or really eating it for a few months. Here and there I would eat it if offered, but it wasn’t really a part of my diet. Thanks to my Dad’s dietary journey, I had always entertained the thought of going vegetarian. Studying here in Newcastle, I’ve met a bunch of vegetarians and vegans, each with their own reasons. I’d done some research, read the papers and looked at the statistics, but I hadn’t found the internal motivation to commit to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I realized how much I valued the environment, the internal motivation came quickly and easily. This was something that &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;, a single person, could do to help the world that I love. So I made the jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a week later, I was on the move again. To the land of roadkill, Tasmania. Contrary to popular belief, Tasmania is actually a state of Australia, not its own country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\images\wo5_05\tazmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;taz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined up with a small group of friends, and with a rental car we toured the island. Ocean coasts and campfires, wildlife sightings and car rides. Nothing can beat the quality time, shared experiences, and bonding that comes from traveling with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/gorge.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Launceston, TA&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/gorge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/mona.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Museum of Old and New Art (MONA)&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/mona.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/swing.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Somewhere along the Northern coast&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/swing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/wallabies.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Carpark Wallabies!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/wallabies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/wineglass.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rainy Wineglass Bay, Freycinet TA&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/taz/wineglass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Tasmania
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Haley, Lauren, Dil and Cameron left for Melbourne, I made my way to Sydney to meet up with my parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so much to cover on the NZ trip, I know that I will end up skimming over the highlights. The trip deserves a post by itself, but in the interests of time, Ill give some updates here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the trip had two obvious benefits, each with a little more complexity than they appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it was amazing to see my parents for the first time in about three months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/marion3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;parents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, that isn’t much longer than a normal school semester in NJ, but the distance does change that a little.  The experience as a whole was a bit bittersweet. It was a reminder of life in the US, for better and worse. With American life comes all the memories of my childhood and family, traditions and culture I’ve lost in my time abroad. There’s a funny thing about culture. It is a function of the people and content you live around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are a bit like fancy sponges in this sense (hang with me), when surrounded with water they slowly absorb it. Take the sponge out of the water and place it on the counter and the sponge does two things. It tries to recreate its old environment, unintentionally, by leaking the water it holds. However, through this process, the sponge slowly absorbs air, which replaces the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in my stay, I’ve lost some of the American, and more specifically, North Eastern, philosophy I was raised upon. Instead I’ve learned from my surroundings and adopted very Australian values. For me, that has been an essential part of my personal growth. Getting a hint of American culture is a gentle reminder of how easily those changes can be swept away through reimmersion. Luckily, people are  a bit more complicated than sponges, so I still stand a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second takeaway from the trip is an affirmation, evidence to support my newfound values. Experiencing nature in dozens of ways, taking in its beauty, and traveling in new ways, gives opportunities to figure out what it is, exactly, that I like to do. Although the roadside beauty of New Zealand was beautiful, I felt like something was missing. Fast forward to a day hike of the Routeburn track (a 4 day route in total), where I found myself immersed in the wild. I figured out what was missing. I like to work for my views. Not only that but there is a peace, serenity, and appreciation that the wild gives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, my parents began asking the tough questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It began simply: “What’s your stance on fish?” At the time, I had no clue. Citing my new values, I decided with environmental interests in mind, there was no difference between fish and other meat. Goodbye sushi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions did not stop there. With my final year of university upcoming, thoughts turned to the future. Two major conclusions rose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need more information to make a decision. This is true with regards to a PhD program and also grad school in general&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t need to compromise my life values and interests in my transition to an “adult” life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess somewhere along the way, we saw some pretty cool stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/beer.jpg&quot; title=&quot;What a shot!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/beer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/bridge.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Taken immediately after sliding into a whirlpool!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beginning of Hollyford track&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/cheers.jpg&quot; title=&quot;If only I could see the picture I was taking...&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/cheers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ferry to Manly&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/devil.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Devil&apos;s Punchbowl&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/devil.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/franz.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Franz Joseph&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/franz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/jurassic.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Jurassic Park?&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/jurassic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/marion.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lake Marion&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/marion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/milfordcrz.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Milford Sound Cruise&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/milfordcrz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/opera3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Trio at the Opera!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/opera3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/reflpond.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mirror &apos;Lakes&apos;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/reflpond.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/routeburn.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Heaven (Routeburn Flats)&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/routeburn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/triangle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Rocks&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/nz_syd/triangle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;New Zealand and Sydney
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving back in Newcastle, adjustment only took a few days. All these affirmations and values, that did exist before the trip, came back with more intensity. Rather than a passive attempt to change my lifestyle, I’m taking things into my own hands.  The result? An exhilarating and busy week.  It was a week that was both incredibly productive, but also a fantastic time. When I look back, I don’t see a trace of the stress and endless work I’m used to. Surfing, Yoga, Wine Tours, Volleyball, Rockclimbing, Board Games and cooking experiments. All balanced with my school work, and 8 hours of sleep? Somehow it all works out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/recent/chillvin.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hunter Valley&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/recent/chillvin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/recent/surf.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Almost froze, but worth it.&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/recent/surf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/recent/vin.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hunter Valley II&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo5_05/recent/vin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Daily Life
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 09:34:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Identity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Identity</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Two Month Mark</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of experiences that mess with your perception of time. Running a marathon, watching a movie, the list goes on and on. The well-worn adage tells us that time flies when we’re having fun. I mean, its a popular quote for a reason, but it’s a little bit limiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I type this, time is ticking forward, slowly bringing the start of week six. If anyone is doing the quick math right now, no its not week six of my trip, but week six of classes. With only seven weeks left before final exams, I think I can say I’ve settled into life here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things that I have learned about my university so far; some majors only last three years. They are well renowned for their engineering department, and frankly I can see why. I also learned that most engineering majors like to take three courses at a time to keep their workload balanced. Coming from the US, I was used to taking more than five classes in addition to working 10 hours a week, so I figured I could handle the four classes with loads of free time to spare. Well, to my surprise, taking four different third year engineering courses has &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; been a cakewalk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unintentionally I loaded myself with one of the most intense schedules possible for any student, not even just for exchange students. The option was either that, or to not come to Aus at all, so frankly I’m not too upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point with all of this is not for pity, but to say that with so much work, I wouldn’t expect time to fly so fast. Working an average of 10 hour days during the week doesn’t exactly sound like a good time.  Its not like I’m skimping on my workload either, I honestly think I been more academically challenged this semester than I ever have in the US. That’s all good, but am I even enjoying my time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve fallen into a balanced routine. Studies, cooking, athletics, social events, and travel have all fallen into their own spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock climbing is still going well, but I also still don’t have video documentation (Sorry Mom!). The pickup volleyball group has inspired a bit of confidence and taught me a bunch. I’ve got a lot to work on, but my spike is looking pretty sharp. I’ve gotten back into running regularly, and hopefully can get my 5k time back to the teens. I can cook at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; four meals from scratch that will impress the average joe. There’s plans in the works for a trip to Tasmania and the outback, with more to come! I’ve hosted brunches and attended dinner parties, gone out for drinks and everything between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I last wrote, I’ve been on a handful of fun trips. First was a three day extravaganza in Sydney, capped by a rainy boat party in the Sydney harbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/boatrain.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rain never stopped anyone&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/boatrain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/bridge_curve.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Photo Credit to Lauren!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/bridge_curve.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo Credit to Lauren!&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/bridge_day_turn.jpg&quot; title=&quot;View from the botanical garden&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/bridge_day_turn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the botanical garden&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/hostel.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Probably the sketchiest hostel in Sydney...&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/hostel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Probably the sketchiest hostel in Sydney...&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/hydefount.jpg&quot; title=&quot;ANZAC Memorial Reflecting Pool&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/hydefount.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ANZAC Memorial Reflecting Pool&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/laurenbridge.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sydney Harbor Bridge with Lauren&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/laurenbridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sydney Harbor Bridge with Lauren&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/ihbutnotih.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Guess what the name of our residence hall is?&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/ihbutnotih.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guess what the name of our residence hall is?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/bridgenight.jpg&quot; title=&quot;No more rain! With Mat and Haley!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/bridgenight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 4&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/harborselfie.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Obligatory&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/harborselfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 4&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/boatparty_medium.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Professional Photographer on scene!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/boatparty_medium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 4&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Photos from our trip to Sydney!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting off the beaten path a little bit, me and my friends made it to Shoal Bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/shoalbay.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Peak of Mt. Tomaree&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/shoalbay.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/shaaaooolll.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Matt with the selfie stick!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/shaaaooolll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Hiking and Beach Day!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the initial lure of canyoning, I couldn’t stay away from it for too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/grouplensflare.jpg&quot; title=&quot;If only I could see the picture I was taking...&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/grouplensflare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/underwaterthumbsup.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Taken immediately after sliding into a whirlpool!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/underwaterthumbsup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Finishing the canyoning trip from a while back
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried my hand at pub TV trivia. I was outclassed by Haley and Saugat in my knowledge of Brooklyn 99 and only got a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; bit of the show spoiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo4_01/b99.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;b99&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When surrounded by beaches, who doesn’t attend a public full moon meditation at sunset?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo4_01/moonmeditation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;moon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t say you’ve partied until you’ve been at a silent disco. Its like a concert with 2 DJ’s playing at once, and if you take off your headphones you can hear everyone singing out of tune:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo4_01/silentdisco.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;disco&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, behind all of these pictures are countless stories, ruined sleep schedules, and good times with a great group of friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/trainstation.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Behind the scenes!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/trainstation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;placeholder image 1&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/frenchtoast.jpg&quot; title=&quot;When 3 people sleep through your brunch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/frenchtoast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/hydewalk.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Nobody told me there was a picture!&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blunt_instruments/assets/images/wo4_01/hydewalk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Do people actually read these?&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Glimpse into the life behind the scenes
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I feel like I’ve done so much, I can remember showing up like it was yesterday. When you’re not constantly thinking about it, but rather spending your time and energy on things you enjoy, its no wonder that you forget to keep track of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 09:34:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Two-Month-Mark</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Two-Month-Mark</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Events, Events, Events</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing that TCNJ can take away from the University of Newcastle (UoN) , its extracurricular events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week before classes started is dubbed “O-Week” and is composed of about 10 days worth of social events, most of which include dorm parties that inevitably lead to a night out on the town. Although the bars and clubs had their own themes throughout the week, the International House (IH) students organized their own twists. “WTF are you wearing”, UV &amp;amp; Fluro, Beach, and Surprise Pair Parties all made an appearance. In addition to these events, the IH upperclassman also organize parties throughout the year in addition to a formal “Commencement” and “Farewell” dinner at the beginning and end of each semester respectively.  In the US, with our drinking age, this type of organization might not be possible. However, it is worth saying that all of these events were a blast. They provided great ways to both make friends and cement a feeling of community amongst 200+ residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/uvparty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;UV Party&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/wtfuwearing_fullbody.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WTF are you wearing?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pool Party&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“O-Week” also included events organized by the university themselves. These ranged from excursions to Blackbutt Wildlife Reserve, to mini surf lessons and more formal orientation style events. These two weeks had an abundant amount of barbies, which have become synonymous with sliced bread and sausage. If you’re adventurous you can go for tomato sauce (&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; ketchup) or BBQ sauce (also not the standard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/blackbutt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wildlife Reserve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/roo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kangaroo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/koala.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Koala&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/seat.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;Surf Lessons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/newy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Newcastle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where UoN thrives, I think, is in its clubs. In particular UNESN, or the University of Newcastle Exchange Student Network, and the Newcastle University Mountaineering Club. UNESN provides excursions around Newcastle throughout the year with each event tailored to exchange students. These include Hunter Valley wine tours, day trips, and rugby matches. The highlight of their lineup is the Sydney Harbor Boat Party coming up in a few weeks. Open bar, Open food and free nightclub tickets. Its gonna be a wild time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mountaineering club on the other hand, is more general. In addition to free nights on the climbing wall, which I have been using liberally, the club organizes day and weekend trips into the heart of Australia for events ranging from canyoning, outdoor rock climbing, hiking, kayaking, and camping. The kicker, all gear and transportation included. You can even rent any of their gear for a trip of your own. I had the chance to go on a beginner Canyoning trip a few days ago, and I can say it was some of the most fun I have had during my time here. Decked out in wetsuits and with drybags in tow we waded, swam, and scrambled through beautiful canyons in the Australian bush. We even ran into a suprise repel (abscel in Australia) down the canyon wall. Luckily, the beginners were surrounded by professional and competent upperclassmen who kept everything running smoothly. Throughout the 12 hr day, I met some super cool people and only got bitten by 1 leech!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/line.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/peace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rest Time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/action.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wading&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/canyon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canyon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/abscel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Abscel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/noshirt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/maccas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dinner Stop at Macca&apos;s&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you exhaust all of the preplanned adventures, you can turn to good old fashioned exploration. With a few friends, I traveled to Sydney (12 AUD = $8.50 for both ways!) for a few days. After visiting Bondi beach, we took a tour of Circular Quay (pronounced “Circular Key”) and the iconic Sydney Harbor Bridge and Opera House. That night, I had my first stay in a hostel. It was surprising and uneventful. Expecting simple group living arrangements I was surprised by how much attention the hostel paid to having a social atmosphere and strong community. Imagine a college dorm turned into a hotel for travelers, and you’ve got it pinned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/board.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bondi pt2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/harborbridgebehind.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sydney Harbor Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/bridgeselfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/opera.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opera House&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/jenga.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jenga Building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/hostelnight1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hostel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/sydneymatt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PC: Matt Dowton&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, sometimes you don’t need to plan anything at all. The amazing thing about social living situations is how spontaneous life can be. Sometimes random encounters turn out best of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo3_04/perogie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Perogie Cooking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward, I have events and tripped planned for almost every weekend of the semester and many of the weekdays. Classes have just begun and, unfortunately, I still have work to do. Yet with the ability to work on the go and get up at a reasonable time, I am confident I will be able to explore to my heart’s content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 08:34:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Events,-Events,-Events</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Events,-Events,-Events</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Lifestyle</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Australia, Mozambique, Zimbabwe, Austria, Germany, France,  Czech Republic, Sweden, Belgium, Poland,  Denmark, United Kingdom, Canada, Fiji, Japan, Nepal, Bhutan and last, but not least, America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 20 years of relative isolation, my first week in the International House has been an eye opening experience. It is easy to look out from the US and say, “Of course Poland is different, that’s Europe. “ or “Swedes don’t speak English, I can’t even understand them .” Rather than try to learn about &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; they are different, we are only acknowledging that they are. It takes people, names, and friends to start to look past that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making so many international friendships isn’t a cakewalk either. Luckily, the University of Newcastle was excellent at providing chances and activities to meet new people, domestic and international. One of the first adventures I undertook around Newcastle was sand dune surfing at Anna’s Bay, just outside the city. After an off road trek through the dunes, we arrived at a crater. After some brief instruction we jumped straight in. Battling against the sandblasts, drawing blood at times, the surfers and snowboarders climbed to the steepest trailhead. While most people rode down the slopes on a slide, just a handful of people chose to ride the hill standing. After many tumbles, almost all of us tamed the slope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_20/dunesurfing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dune Surfing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without the school organizing events, there were still plenty of opportunities to hang out with other people. A short bus ride down the road, Newcastle is home to a half dozen world class beaches. Merriweather, in particular, is exceptionally well known for its surf. In the tail end of summer, the beach has been a haven. With waves over ten feet tall at times, I’m not sure I will ever adjust to the beaches back in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_20/aussybeachgroup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lessons&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_20/surf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bodyboarding&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_20/self.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beach Selfie&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_20/race_applecore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scavenger Hunt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After attending all of these events, meeting so many people, I think I’ve learned my first lesson. While it is always nice to know that I can hang out with someone from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theherald.com.au/story/5910649/warm-welcome-for-university-of-newcastles-international-students-to-kick-off-o-week/&quot;&gt;Iowa&lt;/a&gt; (Shoutout to Haley), its not what I travelled to do. Talking to Australians especially, and experiencing their culture, you can tell just how much more relaxed their lives are. America is always “go go go”, a world where you have leap from one accomplishment to another in search of fulfilment. To us, happiness has always been promised to the externally successful: CEO’s, Doctors, Engineers, Lawyers. For some people, that might be true. Either way, most people felt the pressure to perform, to excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming to Australia, this first week has been one of the most relaxed of my life. There are a handful of events per day, and after that people play life by ear. Head to the beach, go grocery shopping, or maybe go out on the town. One night, I said to a friend “Australians are so much more chill than the US, this is the most relaxing week I’ve ever had.” He looked at me like I was crazy. For him, orientation week at university was the &lt;strong&gt;most&lt;/strong&gt; stressful time of his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conversation went much further, but that interaction set the tone. In Australia, there is no competition for who is better than the next person, not in your GPA or degree, not in anything. You post pics because they are funny, not to show off where you are on vacation or your food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without travel, without meeting and reaching out to all of these people, that’s something you never would have realized. Sure Australia is so far away that it must be different, but that will never help you until you know why its different. Until you can see, for example, that there is more than one way to live your life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 08:34:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Lifestyle</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Lifestyle</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Beginnings</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Travelling 10,000 miles from your home in a single trip is slightly intimidating. Among the last minute packing, goodbyes, and stress I made sure to download oodles, yes oodles, of content for me to devour on the flight. In my mind, I was treating it the same as any other vacation me and my family had been on. I’ve been blessed enough to have taken my fair share of lengthy flights, and each one was filled with movies and books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So naturally, I considered myself an expert in all things travel entertainment. As an avid book reader and fledging movie enthusiast, this was a dangerous game. Somehow, I rationalized that I could use 24 entire hours, not considering the possibility of you know, talking to people or maybe sleep?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to my departure I had downloaded 4 new kindle books, 2 podcast episodes, and 6 movies. All of this, not including any other in flight entertainment, set for a promising trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, after reaching cruising altitude I would get comfortable and begin the distractions. Yet, for this entire trip, despite the massive preparations, I watched only 3 movies (none of which I had prepared on my laptop) and finished a single audiobook. For 30 hours of travel, that was only 20% of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the other 80%, I made a spontaneous to do something different for once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flying over the grand canyon, the snow capped foothills and frozen lands of the Midwest, I sat and watched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_09/plane.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;plane&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it takes a change in perspective to open our eyes. As I looked at the millions flakes of snow coating the land as far as the eye could see, the highways reduced to faint lines, I was humbled. There is something about stepping back (or up) that makes you philosophical. Mountains and rivers, ravines, forests and everything between. The water and nitrogen cycles, climate and weather, ecology, all insanely complex systems overlapping perfectly. After staring at the world below me for hours I couldn’t help but think that maybe my worries might not be that important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after getting bored with attempts at self enlightenment, I still kept the distractions at bay. Seated next to me on my flight to LA was a young man. He looked like a college freshman, dressed to the T, tie and all. Throughout the flight we eased into conversation. I learned he was a student at USC, where he had just moved from Baltimore. He actually lived within 20 min of LAX where he commuted to school. Coincidentally, he was also an engineering student. For the rest of the flight we kept up a light conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, his phone died. I had noticed before he wasn’t really prepped for a 5 hour flight. All he had was his phone. Soon after he asked me if I had a charger. I lent him my small cable and the flight continued on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we near LAX, somewhat out of the blue, he asks if I have had dinner. It was an odd question, but I just said no, not yet. He had decided that in exchange for the charger, he wanted me to get a taste of LA. I resisted, but he insisted. We exchanged numbers and he left. I was skeptical. An hour and a half later, after a cab ride to his house and a stop at In and Out burger, he showed up at Terminal B of LAX. You’re the bomb Eman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/wo2_09/inout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;inout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say that 15 hours of flying, for anyone considering the trip, was not bad at all. It started out with a meal service. Vegetable curry at 1AM local time wasn’t too bad. Then the lights were dimmed and people settled in. For most of the trip, the entire cabin slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this flight, I leaned a little more on my entertainment options. When the entire plane is asleep at 7am, with all the windows closed, I didn’t have a ton of options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the crew raised the lights in the final hours of the flight, they began meal service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to me for the entire flight had been a young lady in her late twenties. From a glance, she was a backpacker returning from a stint abroad. As the trip went on, we too eased into conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Melbourne local, she had moved from England after attending “Uni” for graphic design and getting her masters in user interfaces. She was on her way back from a 6 month backpacking trip in South and Central America. Colombia (which has the best hostels for those wondering), Mexico, Guatemala, you name it. The final hours of the flight were filled with discussion on American and Australian culture, spots to visit across the country, and stories. I think the crash course will help me cheat the learning curve a little. For example, who knew there was an Ozone hole above the continent? Everyone here wears a minimum of SPF 50. Tips like this were invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all you travelers, take a minute to stop and smell the roses. The best memories and experiences don’t always happen where you expect them.  Maybe its on the hike or at the beach, on the events you had been looking forward to for ages, but maybe its on the bus or at a restaurant. Just maybe, it’s in the little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an open mind. Keep exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 17:19:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Beginnings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Beginnings</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Nuts and Bolts</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For those curious, I am using GitHub Pages to host the site, which is composed in two separate sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resume/Bio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first section is built using a modified bootstrap template dating back from my summer at CMU. The resume portion of the website gave me a quick and dirty rundown on &lt;strong&gt;CSS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HTML&lt;/strong&gt;. And by quick and dirty, I mean I have only just enough knowledge to be dangerous, but not enough to have any clue what exactly is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog however, is built using Jekyll, a static site generator. Here I integrated a Jekyll template made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/&quot;&gt;minimalmistakes&lt;/a&gt;. Most of this work involved learning some &lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt; (AKA downloading it and copying commands). Finally, the comment section required some basic &lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Liquid&lt;/strong&gt; manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I probably spent &lt;em&gt;30 hours&lt;/em&gt; on the bio and &lt;em&gt;15 hours&lt;/em&gt; on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 17:19:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/site-construction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/site-construction</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to my Blog</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After what seems like an unnecessary amount of struggle and headache, I finally have my travel blog up and running!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve made your way here, feel free to bookmark this site on your browser for easy access. If that is too difficult, you can always navigate here from &lt;a href=&quot;https://blakecapella.com&quot;&gt;https://blakecapella.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;blakecapella.com&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blog&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Posts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure many of you have tons of questions about my trip! Rather than try and explain them to everyone individually, I included some pretty pictures and links to cool resources explaining everything in more detail and honestly, more accurately than I probably could. This FAQ page can be found on the top bar of the site. The FAQ page is also the very first page you are directed to from https://blakecapella.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions that aren’t addressed in the FAQ, feel free to reach out to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case you forgot my various email addresses, etc., They can be found next to my picture on this page along with all other blog posts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;itinerary&quot;&gt;Itinerary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be uploading an itinerary hopefully as my next post. However, be aware that my goal is to be spontaneous! That means I am not exactly sure where I will be and when. However, you will still be able to follow along with all my posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.australia.com/content/australia/en/events/sports-events/surfest/_jcr_content/imageMapWithCityLink/image.img.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture alt&quot; title=&quot;Cool Picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am super excited for the trip! With a few weeks left in winter break, I feel like I still have so much to do.  The weeks will fly by, and Ill be posting again sooner than I think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Posted!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 17:19:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Ghost</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 03:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/welcome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the Ghost editor</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you&apos;ll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You&apos;ll also notice that there&apos;s a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let&apos;s run you through some of the basics. You&apos;ll want to make sure you&apos;re editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we&apos;ve used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you&apos;re well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;insertingimages&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they&apos;re prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Markdown editors don&apos;t make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it&apos;s always a good idea to make sure your images aren&apos;t gigantic files &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; uploading them to Ghost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;makinglists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an omellete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;addingquotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might&apos;ve seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they&apos;ll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividingthingsup&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you&apos;re still curious about more advanced tips then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/advanced-markdown/&quot;&gt;Advanced Markdown Guide&lt;/a&gt; - or if you&apos;d rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we&apos;ve got a overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/using-tags/&quot;&gt;how to use Ghost tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/the-editor</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-editor</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Organising your content with tags</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&apos;t matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don&apos;t necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost&apos;s extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/using-tags</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/using-tags</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Managing Ghost users</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; users. If you don&apos;t trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn&apos;t invite them to Ghost admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editors&quot;&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;administrators&quot;&gt;Administrators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;theowner&quot;&gt;The Owner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/managing-users</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/managing-users</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Making your site private</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;ve got a publication that you don&apos;t want the world to see yet because it&apos;s not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost&apos;s General Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png&quot; alt=&quot;private&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you&apos;re working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do remember though, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; secure authentication. You shouldn&apos;t rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It&apos;s just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/private-sites</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/private-sites</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Advanced Markdown tips</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;ve gotten pretty comfortable with &lt;a href=&quot;/the-editor/&quot;&gt;all the basics&lt;/a&gt; of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you&apos;ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we&apos;re using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;strike through&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;highlight&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingcodeblocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullbleedimages&quot;&gt;Full bleed images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a &lt;code&gt;#hash&lt;/code&gt; value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is styled with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it&apos;s a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;referencelists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creatingfootnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullhtml&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you&apos;re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here&apos;s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 22:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/advanced-markdown</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/advanced-markdown</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your own Ghost theme</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a totally custom design for your publication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketplace.ghost.org&quot;&gt;Ghost Theme Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, or you can simply create your own from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://marketplace.ghost.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/marketplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;marketplace&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like &lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, for example, outputs the name of the current author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TryGhost/Casper&quot;&gt;the source code for Casper&lt;/a&gt;, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;default.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;post.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the file used in the context of viewing a post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;index.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the file used in the context of viewing the home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&apos;ve got &lt;a href=&quot;http://themes.ghost.org/docs/about&quot;&gt;full and extensive theme documentation&lt;/a&gt; which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there&apos;s also a &lt;strong&gt;#themes&lt;/strong&gt; channel in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.ghost.org&quot;&gt;public Slack community&lt;/a&gt; which we always recommend joining!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/themes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/themes</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Businessman &amp; The Fisherman</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;An American businessman took a vacation to a small coastal Mexican village on doctor’s orders. Unable to sleep after an urgent phone call from the office the first morning, he walked out to the pier to clear his head. A small boat with just one fisherman had docked, and inside the boat were several large yellowfin tuna. The American complimented the Mexican on the quality of his fish.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 03:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/the-businessman-and-fisherman</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-businessman-and-fisherman</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Full and Comprehensive Style Test</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 03:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>I Have a Dream</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to join with you today in what will go down in history as the greatest demonstration for freedom in the history of our nation.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 1963 03:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/i-have-a-dream</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/i-have-a-dream</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Purpose of Education</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 1948 03:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/the-purpose-of-education</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-purpose-of-education</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Out to Sea</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I had this story from one who had no business to tell it to me, or to any other. I may credit the seductive influence of an old vintage upon the narrator for the beginning of it, and my own skeptical incredulity during the days that followed for the balance of the strange tale.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 1912 02:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/out-to-sea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/out-to-sea</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Looking-Glass house</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing was certain, that the white kitten had had nothing to do with it:— it was the black kitten’s fault entirely. For the white kitten had been having its face washed by the old cat for the last quarter of an hour (and bearing it pretty well, considering); so you see that it couldn’t have had any hand in the mischief.
The way Dinah washed her children’s faces was this: first she held the poor thing down by its ear with one paw, and then with the other paw she rubbed its face all over, the wrong way, beginning at the nose: and just now, as I said, she was hard at work on the white kitten, which was lying quite still and trying to purr — no doubt feeling that it was all meant for its good.
But the black kitten had been finished with earlier in the afternoon, and so, while Alice was sitting curled up in a corner of the great arm-chair, half talking to herself and half asleep, the kitten had been having a grand game of romps with the ball of worsted Alice had been trying to wind up, and had been rolling it up and down till it had all come undone again; and there it was, spread over the hearth-rug, all knots and tangles, with the kitten running after its own tail in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 1871 02:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/looking-glass-house</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/looking-glass-house</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Down The Rabbit Hole</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Alice was beginning to get very tired of sitting by her sister on the bank, and of having nothing to do: once or twice she had peeped into the book her sister was reading, but it had no pictures or conversations in it, ‘and what is the use of a book,’ thought Alice ‘without pictures or conversation?’&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 1865 02:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/down-the-rabbit-hole</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/down-the-rabbit-hole</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Gettysburg Address</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Fourscore and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 1863 02:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
